<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>t.ekeh</title>
    <description>Personal Webpage</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Active Energetics (in progress)</title>
        <description>
          
          Let us call the ABP potential function. This can take various forms depending on the model. Let’s impose that and its derivative is zero at the wall for all The steady state Fokker Plank equation for this system is then Even without the active propulsion, there is still some peculiarity...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-04-01-active-energetics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-04-01-active-energetics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Curl Forces in Cyclic Protocols</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose we have the followinf Fokker plank equation in a confined system assuming a zero flux in space (from confinement) we can write straight away the equation We can decompose any vector field into a curl-free and divergence components i.e . We can similarly solve Eq \ref{eqn:FP} by splitting for...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 10:27:50 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-31-work-curl-forces/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-31-work-curl-forces/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thermal Beads</title>
        <description>
          
          A simple calculation to help me understand something larger. Suppose there are two beads in between two parallel walls which can move in one dimension perpendicular to the plane of the walls. They are connected together by elastic spring with strength , and each is further connected to the wall...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-22-thermal-beads/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-22-thermal-beads/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stress Functions</title>
        <description>
          
          In this post we’ll discuss a certain description of stresses in 2D mechanical systems, which has proved useful in the study of granular systems and other such packings in mechanical equilibrium. It is called the Airy stress function , . Consider the stress tensor of an arbitrary 2D system which...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-22-stress-functions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-22-stress-functions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Optimal Finite Time Processes for Active Brownian Processes</title>
        <description>
          
          The Fokker Plank is The work done on the system in time is simply Where are the controllable parameters. Following Seifert, we first consider two special cases Example 1: Translational Harmonic Trap Call and . The work becomes Multiplying by x in Eq \ref{eqn:fp} and averaging gives the relation ....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 02:19:42 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-07-active-finite-time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-07-active-finite-time/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Message passing d-dim</title>
        <description>
          
          Previously, a loose connection between informational message passing and ordering in 1D ising spin chains was discussed. We left of wondering about the connection to higher dimensional spin systems. Hypercubic Lattice Using the previous considerations it’s possible to bound the position of the phase transition. suppose we are links away...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 02:18:28 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-07-message-passing-d-dim/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-07-message-passing-d-dim/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Title</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 02:17:26 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-07-template/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-07-template/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stochastic Search</title>
        <description>
          
          A basic sort of computatinla problem is that of searching for a specific elemnt within a larger list of elements Many algorithms exist to complete this task, but here we will investigate the usefulness of a certain type of Stochastic Search Algorithm which are algorithms which make use of randomness....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 01:05:31 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-06-stochastic-resonance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-06-stochastic-resonance/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ginzburg for Levy Flight Rheology</title>
        <description>
          
          See this previous post for a description of the physical set up and problem to be investigated. Approaches The mean field arguments and models siplify a calculation by ignoring the spatial structure present. To consider the effect of spatial information, we can introduce small, position dependent fluctuations and see how...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 12:53:06 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-03-04-ginzburg-levy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-03-04-ginzburg-levy/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Title</title>
        <description>
          
          Basic Model Imagine a stochastic reset of a certain type. Each site of our rheologicla material has a stress associtaed with it, but due to mechanical noise (rather than thermal fluctations) the stress at each site is going to fluctuate according to some effective Stochastic ODE. I.e for each site...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 03:10:46 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-21-resets/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-02-21-resets/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rheology with Levy Flights</title>
        <description>
          
          Premise I recently came across a paper which investigates rheological properties of a material using a stochastic Levy flight process. To construct this mean field theory, it first starts by considering discretised space, with each cell/block/site taking some local stress value . As the elastic system undergoes relaxation, or local...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-21-rheology-levy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-02-21-rheology-levy/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Integrals over All Directions</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 07:08:58 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-18-angular-averages/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-02-18-angular-averages/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gaussian Mixtures</title>
        <description>
          
          Arguably one of the simplest, nicest to work with distributions is that of a Gaussian. Within the field of stochastic ODEs, the common stochastic noise (the Weiner process) is simply a Guassian distributed point process. But depending on the system in question, a systems noise could be distributed differently. Some...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-15-gaussian-mixture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-02-15-gaussian-mixture/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>topic ideas</title>
        <description>
          
          Roughly in order of interest. There are other things of interest but these are just possible projects/vague directions i could identify Upper Critical Dimension (UCD) for Mean Field Rheological Models Background Jie Lin and Wyart published Mean Field Description of Plastic Flow in Amorphous Solids , where they calculated an...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-13-topics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-02-13-topics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ABP pdf</title>
        <description>
          
          This is a calculation to determine the probability density of non-interacting, elliptical ABPs in a harmonic box trap. The Fokker Plank (FP) is In the wall: Assume Boltzmann weighted In bulk () use a series solution Where we’ve used the symmetry about centre of the box. Continuity of spatially leads...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-04-notepad_rough/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-02-04-notepad_rough/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Title</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose we have a Brownian Motion on a ring. The stochastic differential equation can be written in the angular coordinate as Where is a non-random constant and is a Weiner process (White gaussian noise). What is the probability that takes some certain value when evolving under this dynamics? We can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 09:09:47 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-30-brownian-ring/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-01-30-brownian-ring/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Classical Analogue of Spin through Differential Geometry</title>
        <description>
          
          Some features of quantum physics, at a passing glance, seem analogous to some corresponding classical system from a phenomenological point of view. Others aspects are free of any classical analogue for us to exploit for intuition. The dynamics of a quantum spin is often an example of a non intuitive...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 12:20:58 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-18-classical-analogue-of-spin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-18-classical-analogue-of-spin/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Integral</title>
        <description>
          
          A function of this form came up while doing calculations on active particle dynamics All the parameters of are non-negative, but the variable can take any real value. The function is defined implicitely in terms of this integral which has no closed form expressions which Mathematica could identify. We can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-17-an-integral/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-17-an-integral/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some 1A NatSci Extension Problems</title>
        <description>
          
          Here are a collection of some problems to try if you find yourself with spare time Magnetic Monopole A particle with electric charge moving through an elctromagnetic field experiences a Lorentz force Magnetic monopoles are hypothetical particles that produce magnetic fields that are not divergencelss (). The magnetic field from...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 11:08:40 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-12-winter-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-12-winter-work/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LDP on Graphs</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 05:51:22 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-05-large-deviations-on-graphs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-05-large-deviations-on-graphs/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
