<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>t.ekeh</title>
    <description>Personal Webpage</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Message passing d-dim</title>
        <description>
          
          Previously, a loose connection between informational message passing and ordering in 1D ising spin chains was discussed. We left of wondering about the connection to higher dimensional spin systems. Hypercubic Lattice Using the previous considerations it’s possible to bound the position of the phase transition. suppose we are links away...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 09:16:49 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-02-19-message-passing-d-dim/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-02-19-message-passing-d-dim/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Funky Symplectics</title>
        <description>
          
          Hamiltonian mechanics occurs on a symplectic manifold, but what does that mean? Well, it means that the manifold created by the coordinate variables is equipped with a differential two-form. Let’s zoom in on this. The canonical coordinates for a mechanical system are denoted by where are the generalised coordinates and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 10:41:34 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-01-01-overdamped-motion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-01-01-overdamped-motion/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Random Decreasing Sequence</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose we have a decreasing sequence defined in the following way. First consider a random number generator that takes a non-negative integer, , as input and returns one of , the choice being made uniformly at random. Now pick some integer and define a sequence of by the recurrence relation:...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021-01-01-random-decreasing-seq/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021-01-01-random-decreasing-seq/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Circumventing Bias</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose you have a coin which has probability of giving heads when it is flipped. If then the coin is called biased. Despite the biased nature of the coin, it is still possible to use it to generate fair “flips”. Consider flipping the coin twice, independently. The sample space with...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-12-27-removing-bias/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-12-27-removing-bias/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stable Distributions</title>
        <description>
          
          From Wikipedia: “Let and be independent copies of a random variable . Then is said to be stable if for any constants and the random variable has the same distribution as for some constants and .” And the distribution of X is called a stable distribution. Under convolution, these distributions...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-12-11-stable-dists/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-12-11-stable-dists/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Partition Function Level Sets</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose I want to find a which satisfies the following sort of equation: where is a constant and is a known real function of the parameters . How might I do so? Here we present one possible approximate route, and briefly analyse the resulting equation. If the exponent has a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-11-21-monge-ampere/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-11-21-monge-ampere/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Entropy post XOR</title>
        <description>
          
          The XOR of two bit strings is a fundamental operation in computational logic and cryptography. For example, when implementing a One Time Pad, we encode a message and secret key as bytes and XOR both of these together. A fundamental fact often used is that the result of a completely...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-07-19-entropy-post-XOR/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-07-19-entropy-post-XOR/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fluctuations and Rheology (1) - Eshelby and Force Balance</title>
        <description>
          
          As a material undergoes a yocal yielding event, the stress redistribution is known to take the form of the Eshelby propogator. This is a quadropolar field decaying in distance as from the point of yield, and was first rationalised within the framework of linear elasticty by Eshelby in 1957. Explicitely...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 05:22:51 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-06-26-eshelby_force_balance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-06-26-eshelby_force_balance/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fluctuations and Rheology (2) - KEP and Force Balance</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is builds on the arguments of the previous ones in this series. Start here. Within the continuum elastic framework, there is a clear idea of force balance, and a clear mathmematical manifestation. In particular, in a previous post, we showed that the the standard Eshelby redistribution kernel is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 05:20:15 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-06-26-KEP_force_balance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-06-26-KEP_force_balance/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Replica Method</title>
        <description>
          
          Systems with some sort of disorder require special methods to deal with, even in the context of equilibrium systems. The free energy contains all information on the systems equilibrium phase behaviour, and in the framework of statistical physics this can be written in terms of the partition function . Where...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:35:15 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-06-23-replica-symmetry/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-06-23-replica-symmetry/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SVD and PDEs</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:35:10 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-06-23-template/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-06-23-template/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tensors with Discrete Symmetries</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose we have a collection of interacting particles, but their interactions are anisotopic. Such a situation is common in nature, as must real things are not featureless spheres, and have interactions which will depends on their relative orientation. From polymers, to liquid crystals, to synthetic pacthed particles and more, anisotropy...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 02:26:18 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-03-16-discrete-symmetry-tensors/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-03-16-discrete-symmetry-tensors/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Plastic Events and Resets</title>
        <description>
          
          Imagine a stochastic reset of a certain type. Each site of our rheologicla material has a stress associtaed with it, but due to mechanical noise (rather than thermal fluctations) the stress at each site is going to fluctuate according to some effective Stochastic ODE i.e for each site (assuming they...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-03-03-resetting-basics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-03-03-resetting-basics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Informational Capacity bounding Physical Fluctuations</title>
        <description>
          
          Part 1 : Background We wish to send some information, say a string of 1’s and 0’s, across a chennel. However this channel is subject to noise, there is no guarantee that the bits we send are preserved. Despite this we might imagine that we could, in general still send...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 03:50:35 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-12-21-capacity-bounds-on-correlators/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-12-21-capacity-bounds-on-correlators/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brownian Ring</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose we have a Brownian Motion on a ring. The stochastic differential equation can be written in the angular coordinate as Where is a non-random constant and is a Weiner process (White gaussian noise). What is the probability that takes some certain value when evolving under this dynamics? We can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 01:08:14 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-12-21-brownian-ring/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-12-21-brownian-ring/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Integrals over Solid Angles (Part 2)</title>
        <description>
          
          In a previous post we considered averaging quantities built from tensors over all angles. We know wish to extend the ideas in that post to integrals of the form where is a second rank tensor, symmetric without loss of generality. Ideally, we would like to reason what the solution looks...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-12-17-angular-averaged-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-12-17-angular-averaged-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Integrals over Solid Angles</title>
        <description>
          
          Oftentimes we must do some form of average to calculate an expected quantity. In this post we’ll consider doing angular averages of scalar functions of vectors in various dimensions. We’ll first consider integrals of the form where the integration domain is over all directions the unit vector can take. These...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-07-28-angular-averaged/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-07-28-angular-averaged/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hyperuniform Structure</title>
        <description>
          
          Suspect Calculation Let be the total density of particles and the density of active particles. The initial model for this dynamics give Using the first equation we FT to yield Integrating up and averaging we can then get the expressions At this point we assume a scaling hypothesis of the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 08:54:23 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-06-20-elsens-calc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-06-20-elsens-calc/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Periodically Sheared Amorphous Systems</title>
        <description>
          
          Background/Priors Periodically sheared repulsive circles undergo a few interesting Non-equilibrium/Off-equilibrium transitions Can be modelled by the following Langevin equations ( Kawasaki and Berthier ). is the periodic shear rate and U describes some interaction potential between the particles. No further hydrodynamics involved - the relaxation time of the flow field...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 02:10:24 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-05-16-meeting__MEC/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-05-16-meeting__MEC/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Absorbing State Transitions</title>
        <description>
          
          An absorbing state (AS) is a state which can not be escaped once entered. If we imagine a Markov chain, then the absorbing state is one which has no outgoing transitions. AS transitions are an example of a non-equilibrium phase transition. In analogy to equilibrium phase transisitions, we can define...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 06:04:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-05-03-absorbing-state/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-05-03-absorbing-state/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
