<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>t.ekeh</title>
    <description>Personal Webpage</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>ABP pdf</title>
        <description>
          
          This is a calculation to determine the probability density of non-interacting, elliptical ABPs in a harmonic box trap. The Fokker Plank (FP) is In the wall: Assume Boltzmann weighted In bulk () use a series solution Where we’ve used the symmetry about centre of the box. Continuity of spatially leads...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-02-04-notepad_rough/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-02-04-notepad_rough/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gaussian Mixtures</title>
        <description>
          
          Arguably one of the simplest, nicest to work with distributions is that of a Gaussian. Within the field of stochastic ODEs, the common stochastic noise (the Weiner process) is simply a Guassian distributed point process. But depending on the system in question, a systems noise could be distributed differently. Some...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 09:18:21 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-30-gaussian-decomp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-01-30-gaussian-decomp/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Title</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose we have a Brownian Motion on a ring. The stochastic differential equation can be written in the angular coordinate as Where is a non-random constant and is a Weiner process (White gaussian noise). What is the probability that takes some certain value when evolving under this dynamics? We can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 09:09:47 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-30-brownian-ring/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-01-30-brownian-ring/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Levy Flights and Non Universality</title>
        <description>
          
          I recently came across a paper which investigates rheological properties of a material using a stochastic Levy flight process. It comes down to considering a system described by the following dynamics (plus some resetting) Where is a noise, although not the usual White Gaussian type. Although , takes values according...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:07:29 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-29-levy-flight-rheology/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-01-29-levy-flight-rheology/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Optimal Finite Time Processes for Active Brownian Processes</title>
        <description>
          
          The Fokker Plank is The work done on the system in time is simply Where are the controllable parameters. Following Seifert, we first consider two special cases Example 1: Translational Harmonic Trap Call and . The work becomes Multiplying by x in Eq \ref{eqn:fp} and averaging gives the relation ....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 05:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-04-active-finite-time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-01-04-active-finite-time/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Message passing d-dim</title>
        <description>
          
          Previously, a loose connection between informational message passing and ordering in 1D ising spin chains was discussed. We left of wondering about the connection to higher dimensional spin systems. Hypercubic Lattice Using the previous considerations it’s possible to bound the position of the phase transition. suppose we are links away...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 08:55:45 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-21-message-passing-d-dim/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-21-message-passing-d-dim/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Classical Analogue of Spin through Differential Geometry</title>
        <description>
          
          Some features of quantum physics, at a passing glance, seem analogous to some corresponding classical system from a phenomenological point of view. Others aspects are free of any classical analogue for us to exploit for intuition. The dynamics of a quantum spin is often an example of a non intuitive...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 12:20:58 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-18-classical-analogue-of-spin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-18-classical-analogue-of-spin/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Integral</title>
        <description>
          
          A function of this form came up while doing calculations on active particle dynamics All the parameters of are non-negative, but the variable can take any real value. The function is defined implicitely in terms of this integral which has no closed form expressions which Mathematica could identify. We can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-17-an-integral/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-17-an-integral/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some 1A NatSci Extension Problems</title>
        <description>
          
          Here are a collection of some problems to try if you find yourself with spare time Magnetic Monopole A particle with electric charge moving through an elctromagnetic field experiences a Lorentz force Magnetic monopoles are hypothetical particles that produce magnetic fields that are not divergencelss (). The magnetic field from...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 11:08:40 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-12-winter-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-12-winter-work/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stochastic Resonance</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 05:52:36 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-05-stochastic-resonance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-05-stochastic-resonance/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LDP on Graphs</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 05:51:22 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-05-large-deviations-on-graphs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-05-large-deviations-on-graphs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Title</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 02:40:32 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-03-ABPs-v-AOUPs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-03-ABPs-v-AOUPs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Non-Conservative Forces</title>
        <description>
          
          Consider the basic force equation of classical mechanics When is derived from the gradient of a potential , this system is integrable. We have at least one conserved quantity (the Hamiltonian ) and the dynamics is restricted to some surface of constant energy in phase space. Once the Hamiltonian is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 03:26:58 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-02-non-conservative-forces/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-02-non-conservative-forces/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Message Passing in 1D</title>
        <description>
          
          Suppose we have a 1D array of N spins on a ring, which can be either or . Suppose further that we fix one of the previously identical spins such that it is . Now inagine that between each pair of spins is a directed information channel that aims to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01-message-passing-1d/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-12-01-message-passing-1d/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Title</title>
        <description>
          
          


        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 12:14:19 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-30-template/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-11-30-template/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recursive Methods in Probability</title>
        <description>
          
          Problems can of course be solved in mutliple ways. Sometimes the natural, methodical solution to a problem is very lengthy, so knowing some tricks is useful. One such trick is recursive reasoning, which can prove useful in certain types of probability problems and puzzles. I like these methods since the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-11-23-recursive-methods-in-probability/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018-11-23-recursive-methods-in-probability/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
